# **SULAMITA MORALES**

Brooklyn, NY 11223 | 616-570-7535 | <u>sulamita@umich.edu</u> | <u>https://github.com/kyusulamita | www.linkedin.com/in/sulamita | https://sulamita.herokuapp.com/</u>

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Proficient: Javascript (ECMAScript 6), C++, React, Redux, Express, Node, Sequelize, Git, HTML5, CSS

Familiar: C#, Python, Heroku, GraphQL, Mocha, Chai, Passport

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Radar | Fullstack engineer | GITHUB: https://github.com/cartographers/Radar

08/2017 - Present

Desktop application built using (React, Redux and Electron)that allows users to visualize Data

• Created and maintained dynamic form that auto populated with most user friendly options and formed raw SQL queries that rendered D3 charts. Made use of React-Redux store state in order to always have up to date information, used local state and component events to make sure data rendered was up to date.

## Which Door? | Sole engineer | GITHUB: https://github.com/kyusulamita/whichDoor

07/2017 - 08/2017

2d Platform puzzle game where player collects coins and attempts to find the right door sequence to escape

Worked on personal codebase. Responsibilities ranged from finding the appropriate sprites and rendering the level correctly, to
coding collision point and physics properties for objects, Implemented finite state machines to deal with main character
rendering. Used Object Oriented Programming to create diverse game, derived 4 enemies from one base class.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Javascript Part Time Instructor | Fullstack Academy | New York, New York

10/2017 - Present

- Head instructor for Intro to Javascript and Google App Script Courses
- Shadow Instructor for Bootcamp Prep course, a month long course that teaches the fundamentals of Javascript more in depth.
- Wrote exam questions on standardized exam that is used to test students ability at the end of Bootcamp course.
- Taught and Mentored 300+ beginner Javascript students

### Fellow | Fullstack Academy | New York, New York

09/2017 - 12/2017

- Taught and mentored 80+ software engineering students across the Fullstack Grace Hopper remote and immersive program
- Conducted technical admissions interviews 2-3x/week, evaluating candidates on technical challenges in Javascript
- Project manager for 4 teams, oversaw development of 2 e-commerce websites and 2 capstone projects

### EFL Lead Teacher | Asamblea San Marcos | San Marcos, Guatemala

09/2016 - 03/2017

- Developed modularized daily lesson plans that could be adapted to suit a variety of skills, intentional mentorship where students who understood subjects more were allowed to help students who were struggling, Incorporated hands on learning.
- Increased English Recognition in 6-7 year old category from 40% to 80% in one month.

# ESL Teacher | Excel English | Ann Arbor, MI

05/2016 - 09/2016

- Directed 6 year old age division as head instructor. Managed over 40 children with 3 in class volunteers.
- Automated student group generation based on monthly test results and compatibility scores in order to minimize class disruption and increase small group learning

# **EDUCATION**

### FULLSTACK ACADEMY - NEW YORK

# **Software Engineering**

05/2017 - 09/2017

- Award: Recipient of Woman Who Code Scholarship
- Incredibly Selective (<8% Acceptance rate). Developed a strong foundational understanding of front-end and back-end development including APIs, closure, scoping, prototypal inheritance, recursion, code optimization, OO JavaScript, data structures, algorithms, asynchronous programming, object relational mappers, schema design, HTTP, test driven development, sessions, authentication, REST APIs, advanced promises, agile project management, and deployment (over 1200 hours of work)

## UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN - Ann Arbor, MI

#### B.A. Spanish(Communication and Thought) | Computer Science Minor

07/2011 - 12/2015

- Award: Recipient of the Michigan Tradition Scholarship for 4.5 years
- Tutored in predominately hispanic high schools in Detroit over the summer, introducing them to engineering products. Went to migrant camps and taught basic math and English to elementary age children in open fields with limited resources.
- Classes Taken: Elementary Programming Concepts, Discrete Mathematics, Programming & Data Structures. Date Structures & Algorithms, Introduction to Computer Organization, Web Database Information Systems, Calc I, II, & III